CRISTIAN SILVA



wd.cristian@gmail.com



(438) 862-7803 (Hey, listen!)



/csdeveloper

CHARACTER PRESENTATION:



As a software developer with an extensive experience in functional analysis and database engineering, I can fit roles from the entire cycle of software creation, from the planning and initial analysis to the implementation of the software.

Results-oriented, I am constantly searching for ways to improve my work-way.

I am a good learner and team player, always willing to share and absorb knowledge from my coworkers, which means that even without deep knowledge in specific areas, I take advantage of the working environment to learn and practice to master the subject faster.

I can offer my background and knowledge as a software developer and business analyst in exchange for learning and starting in the video game development area, something that was always a goal for my carrier.

Check more visiting https://github.com/csprofile

SKILLS:

Javascript (Client & Server) Database Development Database Administration

PHP C#

Unity 3D HTML & CSS

Team and Project Management Photoshop & Graphic Design



8 years of experience 8 years of experience

4 years of experience 3 years of experience

3 years of experience Hobby experience

Hobby experience

4 years of experience 2 years of experience

SOFT SKILLS:

- Team Player *10
 Communication *9
 Criativity *8
- Social Interaction +10Organization +9
- LeadershipAttention to Details

EDUCATION:

- Computer Technician Degree: Ql Technical Schools, RS - Brazil (2008)
- Technologist Degree in System Analysis and Development: FAQI, RS - Brazil (2014)
- Several online courses about leadership, conflict management and human behavior



PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

SFCC Backend Developer | Business Analyst

OSF Global Services 04/2017 - Present

Backend Developer: Backend development using the Salesforce clouds platform.

Business Analyst: Translate business requirements to technical solutions.

Technologies: Javascript, Salesforce, Demandware.

Freelancer Software Engineer

Toptal

10/2015 - 01/2018

Develop projects to different clients in different platforms and environment.

Technologies: Javascript, C#, SQL Server

Profile: https://toptal.com/resume/cristian-silva

Full-Stack Developer

CWI Software

6/2015 - 4/2017

Worked as part of a team that developed a highly complex system for a Brazilian bank. This system is responsible for credit and debit transactions in current accounts and generates indicators that assist in the company's decision-making.

Restructured the billing system that includes a data model, performance improvement, and increasing flexibility to the business.

Technologies: C#, Javascript, Reporting Services, MSSQL Server, SQL Server Tuning Advisor, Oracle DB, Jenkins

CT0 | Founder

Q3 Performance Solutions

10/2014 - 06/2015

Worked developing a system that gets data in real-time from measuring machines and analyzing dimensional deviant symptoms, generating alerts, historic charts and statistics in friendly and customizable dashboards.

The system reduced the cost of a multinational car manufacturer's recall in half a million dollars per month.

Technologies: C#, .NET Framework, MSSQL Server, Javascript, jQuery, Highcharts, CSS3, HTMLS

Teacher

QI Technical schools

01/2010 - 12/2011 and 06/2015 - 05/2016

Created educational content, activities, and projects for students of varying levels of age and knowledge on systems development in the field of computer tech.

Technologies: Java, T-SQL, HTML, CSS3, PHP, Android Studio

Full-Stack Developer

NC Production Systems

01/2010 - 10/2014

Created a multiplatform terminal to get data from machines or employees of factory floor and generate dashboards to decision making of production segmentation.

Developed a friendly and customizable web system to provide data and reports in realtime.

Created a communication layer between client ERP (TOTVS, SAP) and company system. Technologies: PHP, MSSQL Server, C#, .NET Framework, JavaScript, jQuery, Highcharts.

Application Support and Implementation

Numericon Manufacturing Systems

08/2007 - 12/2009

Implemented and supported 2S projects including national and multinational companies. Technologies: T-SQL, Visual Basic 6

BONUS:

First authorial game: I have created this game for a Hackathon in 2016. The game has been created in 24 hours using pure Javascript and CSS -> https://csprofile.github.io/rightway/